澄心委员会（二）
但直截了当地说，澄心委员会
But to cut to the chase, the Clearness Committee is
基本上是一种探索内心存在状态的模式。
basically an inquiry model of being in the world.
我想说的是，
And I like to say
特别是在学术环境中，
especially that in academic setting that
澄心委员会通过
what a Clearness Committee does with an individual
提出诚实而开放的问题
by way of inquiring honestly
帮助案主倾听自己内心
and openly into who that individual is
以及内在导师要说什么。
and what that individuals inner teachers has to say.
这也是一个学者
It's the same posture that
会采取的姿态，一个伟大的学者
a scholar adopts, a great scholar adopts
对他/她所研究领域所采取的姿态。
toward whatever it is that he or she is studying.
如果你是一名物理学家，你在这个世界上
If you're a physicist you're not in the world
不是为了找到一个亚原子粒子，
to locate a subatomic particle and then tell it
然后告诉它应该做什么或告诉它的性质是什么。
what it's supposed to be doing or tell it what its nature is.
伟大的物理学家实际上
Great physicists actually
是在倾听他们试图理解的事物。
listen to the thing they're trying to understand.
他们有这样一种热情，
And they have such a passion
要根据事物本性去理解它，
about understanding that thing on its own terms
而不会强加错误的分类给它。
without imposing false categories on it.
他们是很好的倾听者,
That they're very good listeners,
伟大的学者总是很好的倾听者,
great scholars are always very good listeners,
因为他们对正在研究之物
because they have such reverence and respect
有如此的崇敬和尊重，
for whatever they are studying that
他们想听它说话，
they want to hear  it into speech,
他们想用它自己的声音与其对话。
they wanted to speak to them in its own voice.
坦率地说，我在大学里的困惑是，
And the  puzzlement for me in universities
为什么我们知道如何将
frankly has been why we know how to
这种尊重扩展到亚原子粒子
extend that respect to subatomic
或文学作品或历史时期中，
particles or bodies of literature or periods of history,
但我们不知道如何彼此尊重。
but we don't know how to respect to each other.
因此，澄心委员会是一个彼此
So the Clearness Committee is an opportunity
为对方做这件事的机会，对我来说，
to do it for each other which seems right
这似乎是正确和恰当的，而且是富有成效的生命奉献。
and proper to me and fruitful life giving.
从组织的角度来说，我认为
In organizational terms, I think
澄心委员会就像一个优秀的
the Clearness Committee is like the
走来走去的领导者，她会这样说,
good leader who walks around basically saying,
“这里发生了什么？
"What's happening here?
你是怎么经历这一切的呢?”，
And how are you experiencing what's happening?",
而且她会非常仔细地倾听，
and listen very carefully in a way that
以帮助人们拿起镜子照自己，
helps people hold a mirror up to themselves
并参与到自我纠正这个
and engage in that most remarkable
人类最了不起的活动中。
human activity called self-correction.
就像你看着镜子里的自己，
Just as you look at yourself in the mirror
看看自己是否达成目标。
to see that you are missing the mark.
不是因为有人告诉你，你没抓住目标,
Not because someone tells you that you're missing the mark,
而是因为你已经知道标的是什么了。
but because you already know what the mark is.
镜子可以帮助你看到你偏离了目标。
And the mirror helps you see there you're off target.
我认为在一个组织中进行领导，
There's a way I think of leading in an organization
或者帮助一个组织了解其自身有一种方式。
or of helping an organization understand its own life.
这更多的是关于镜像，而不是
That is much more about mirroring than it is
关于建议、修正、拯救和纠正每个人。
about advising, fixing, saving and setting everybody straight.
镜像是很强大的，因为当
And mirroring is powerful, because when
人们在镜子中看到自己，
people see themselvess in the mirror and
并参与到这种被称为自我纠正、
engage in that activity called self-correction
自我分析或自我理解的活动中时，
or self-analysis or self-understanding,
其结果更有可能是永久和深刻的，
the results are much more likely to be permanent and deep
而不是当一些局外人出现并说，
than they are when some outsider comes along and says,
”哦，你把一切搞错了,
"Oh, you got this all wrong,
你最好这样做!”
better you should do it this way!",
人们可能会做一两个星期，
which people may do for a week or two and then
然后他们又恢复到其更舒服的状态中。
they'll revert to whatever it is they're more comfortable with.